谨以此片追忆逝去的童年，如果你也有这样的童年的话欢迎加入我们的贴吧"神剑传奇"。本作品之片源来自互联网，版权归原公司所有。任何组织和个人不得公开传播或用于任何商业盈利用途，一切后果由该组织或个人承担！制作者不承担任何法律及连带责任！请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
传
France 2. Ettipsc Animat ion. Toonean PRoduct ions XIl Ins
FE
翻译：英语辅导频道
输入/时间轴/压制：harry159821/黑月
SCRIDC
Beniamin Legrand
pc by
Benjamin LeGrand
校对：
p
B
tHiamin
Legrand
This barbarian sword of yours
isn't quite the same
aliber
这把海上族使用的剑和神剑不一样了
e
t's a poor worker
who blames her tools
差劲的工人才会抱怨工具不好用
That's better!
了
Now you ve g
见在你技巧了
Not bad Djana.
You're still quite a
fighter\even without
即使没有神剑你也是个不错的斗
Diana?
楼哪你怎么了
Drama
公K
You're not having
second thought
你不重新考虑
You are still giving
back to the=king?
你还是打算把神剑交给国王吗
Of course sher is
她当然要
The kingdom is peaceful. calm
现在整个王国很安宁平静
Not even
f black magics anywhere
没有一点邪恶势力的迹象
except for Kwodahn's
spell on my father.
除了科沃达在我父王身上下的魔咒
How can break
it without xcalibur?
没有神剑我要如何破解它呢
第？集
Wonit you reconsider, Herik
你不重新考虑下吗哈里克
The! People of the Sea
are part of the kingdom now
海上族现在是王国的量份子了
but still they must
have their own leader
可他们得有自己的首领
You are the logical choice
你是最合理的
thank you, Your Majesty
多谢您的美意王后陧
but have no
wish to succeed my father
不过我井没有糕原接替我父亲的位置
No one ever listens to
kings and queens anymore./
没有谁愿意听从国和主后的命令了
Mamalook
Xcalibur's place
母后快看放置神剑的机关自动打开了
Look how shiny it is
看它多耀眼啊
Somethimg's going or
有情
juo bob s, buenos
Something,'s going/on
情要发了
k
The Shogi Master
The Final Combat is upon us.
最后战终手来临了
when the/ Book and the
Sword are in their places.
精灵和法师会再次联手
And never again will kwodahn
科达就永远不会再
Why has it stepped?
么就了呢
The Final Combat is upon us
最后战即来临
The Book keeps
repeating the same message
生命书不复同信
When the Book and the
Sword are in their places
当生命之和神剑回原位时候
And never again will Kwodahn
剧默达就永不会
Che ng
oh。no
Oh, nol
h。mo
「不
不
What Master?
Kwodahn will never again wha
什么大法师科沃达永远不会怎么啊
Herik? What's happening
里
么回事
djon't know, Your Majesty
我不知道王后陛下
the Book of Life
blocked, somehow
生命之书象是被锁住了
CAndsit has something
th xcalibur
是跟神剑有的
must reach Princess Djana
as quick
kly as possible
我得尽快赶去娜公主身
平
们
is a beautiful sword. tara
这把剑很漂亮塔拉
and I' do appreciate it, but
我确实喜欢可
You don't want it
不想要吗
You can keep it until
I've returned Xcalibur
在我交还神剑之前你帮我保管它吧
Djanal Tara
表塔拉
Something tells me
that might take a. while
alyM e aye I6ue业
eui'slle) 6uqiewos
t Something tells
that' might take a while
样子抢红一了
Herik, how is
Arthus doing? Fine.
哈里克阿瑟斯怎样了挺好的
AT-heret's going to be a
ceremony tomorrow evening
uquaAa Moo wUo) UowUBaa
Therel's going to be a
ceremony tomorrow.
明
6ujuawa MOJOLUOT AUoUUeJao
Thereis going to be a
ceremony tomorow-evening
明天会有个式
o Diana can hand
Xcaliburover to hi
到时候娜可以地神剑
给阿期下
As for me, I turned down the
Sea Prince title I was offered
至于我我拒绝海王子的头
But that's what your
father would have wished
可那正是你父亲所期望看到的
know
我知道
And know everyone
thinks it should be me
我知道大家都认为我是最合适的入选
but just feel that
my destiny lies elsewhere
但是我只是觉得自己的命运不在那里
It's your choice Herik
你自己决定哈里克
I'l tell Morgan and the People
of the Sea about tomorrow night
去通知莫刚和海上一族有明晚的事
See you then
到时候见
Djana. you have to bring
Xcalibur to the palace right away?
裘娜你得马上把神剑送回王宫
Look!
看这里
The Final Combat is upon us.
最后一战即将来临
球智一
sn-uodn-s! 1Bquoo: ay1
The Final Combat is upon us
最后一战即将来临
when the Book and the
Sword are in their places
精灵和法师将会再次联手
And never again willskwodalmone
科沃达就永远不会再
The end of the
message is missing!
口信的最部分消线
is missing
国信的最质部分消
The end ofthe
message Is missing
囗信的最后部分消失
What does it mean?
是什么意思呢
It means that
despite the apparent calm
意味着现在虽然看似风平静
Kwodahn is
preparing something terrible
但是科沃达肯定在预谋更可怕的事
Consider yourself warned, Princess
自己承担风险哦公主殿下
Be sure to
enjoy your final hours
好好享受你最后的几个小时吧
You heard the
装表动那你也到大质的
Shogi Mastero-Djanao
Be reasonable for once
次讲点道里好不
No,have unti
tomorrow to return calibur.
不行我明天才会交还神剑
still have a
chance to free my father
我还有机会救我父王
And how do you
/ propose to do that
那你准备怎么做呢
Herik. look! I' kr
哈里克看我就知道
Nothing is over yet
例都还爱有结束呢
Kyodan is stil here!
科怀在这里
t's a signa
仪是征兆
四Q
t's a sigml
这是布兆
Djamao-pleasea
Djana, plea
哪尔
回 anan p
求你
a
Djana, please
表那
Djana
Dana, please
Justice
让神剑回刃原位吧
Re自Swod
Return the Sword f
ustc
神剑回归原位吧
Justice
siplace
进神剑回原位吧
Return the- Sword
Justice to its placen
让神剑回归原位吧
and let the Shogis and the
ylphs take care of- kwvodahn
然后法师就可以和精灵联付料达
One more day. Herik
给多我一天时间
One more day with calibur
给多天时间
find Kwodah'
andsdestroy him mysel
让我拿着神剑去找科沃达然后消灭他
Just for the record
I'm on your side this time
明确一点这次我支持你
the Shogi: Master
can't tell us any more
如果大法师不能告诉我们更多信息
maybe the Sylphs can
也许精灵可以
Djana will- never
bring back Xcalibur
裘娜绝不会交还神剑的
And I will destroy this kingdom
这样一来我就可以毁灭整个王国
The time has
come for my revenge
我报复的时候到了
All who dared resist me
任何胆敢反抗我的人
from the royal
Palace to the villages,
上至王室下至平民
destroy them all!
统统给我干掉
May the Duel begin!
决斗即将开始
Hurry. Djana
There's' no time to lose
快点裘娜没有时间了
Mother, help me!
母后帮帮我
Kwodahn made the
statue of father disappear
科沃达让父王的石雕消失了
Flip Hac fiEr
请整装哪达
Help me free
him and crush Kwodahn!
请帮我救出父王消灭科沃达
At lastovo the moment is upon
us when all will be decided
决定一切的时刻终于来临了
Mother
I'don't know what to do
母后我不知道怎么办
need your advice.
我需要你的建议
You don't have much time
你没有多少时间耽搁了
It has already begun
已经开始了
Another page-cannot be turned.
直到所有借的东两回归原位
TaoImihat's-banowedi'hereturned
才能翻新的
p
=
But the knight will show the way
可是会有位骑士引路
His efforts with a blow repay
他的努力即将得到回报
As the brothers reunite
兄弟重聚的时候
put up your sword
and end your figh
举起你的剑结束决
The selfless act that sets you free
无私的举动会让你自由
poem and a riddle
首诗迷
understand the Imp
language better than Sylphs
相比精灵语言我对捣蛋鬼们语言
的理解更好点
No one promised us fighting
Kwodahn would be easy, Wip.
威普没会说对付科沃达是件容易的事
We just haye to
interpret what they- told us
我们只需要理解她们给了我们什么提示
You're right
It,'s not gonna be easy
说得对确实没那么容易
s
Another page cannot be turned
新的一页翻不过来
That part's simple enough,
那一句很容易理解
the Book of Life
doesn't work any longer
生命之书不再起作用了
More trouble than
t was worth, if you ask me
如果你们问我我认为生命之书
带来的麻烦更多
Oh excuse me
breathing fire
噢不好意思我又喷火
Till all that's
borrowed is returned
直到借来的东西回归原位
I'll return the Book to
its place in the monastery
我会把生命之书放回三基寺
You return the sword to Arthus
而你把神剑交还给阿瑟斯
Diana?
裘娜怎么了
Just take care of the Book
你就只管保护好生命之书吧
After that. we' ll see
我们等着瞧好了
What's that
那是什么
Look over there
快看那边
-Oh no! Golgotha
是兽兵
They're coming from every
rywherel
他们从四处涌过来了
Quick, run!
快跑
The Golgotha
are attacking the village!
兽兵进攻我们村子
Raise the alarm!
大家武b起来
Get your weapons!
Defend yourselves
大家拿起武器自卫
Oh. no!
噢不要
Look! It's Djana and Herik!
看是裘娜和哈里克
Fire emanations, fly
火球去
Fire emanate
Fire emanations, fly!
球去
Thank you, my friends
多谢了朋友们
Look! They're going!
瞧他们跑了
I can't get over
how much those things stink.
我真受不了那些东西带来的臭味
Arpad!
阿帕德
Get everyone to take
shelter at the Royal Palace
带大家去王宫避难吧
Don'tawaste any timel
They'lI probably be back
不要拖延时间了他们随时可能回来
C
Promise me you'll go
straight to the royal palace
答应我你会直接去王宫
And don't take on Kwodahn
Not while you're alone!
不要找科沃达硬拼
尤其是你一个人的时候
Hey, what do you - mean alone?
嘿你说的一个人是什么意思啊
She's got a high-flying
fire-breathing dragon to protect her
还有条善飞能喷火的龙保护她呢
Don't worry, Herik
不要担心哈里克
I have Wip to protect me
有威普保护我
and still have Xcalibur
untill give it back to Arthus
而且交还给阿瑟斯之前神剑还在我手里
Good luck!
祝你好运了
What about me
那我呢
走
Let,'s go, Jolie
我们走茱莉
E
入
The Book of Life!
生命之书
Prepare to land!
准备靠岸
国后桶
都品框
城动
密强幅s
3破城
幅器
品
E
订图
So many birds!
那么多鸟
Tara. Look!
塔拉
They've.go
something in their claws.
些乌抓着什么东西
They're attacking us!
他们朝我们进攻了
Those are
odahn's birds!
那
达的鸟兵
We have to head for land! Quick!
我得赶快靠岸快
Lower the lifeboats
把救生船放下来
Look at that
看那边
/e 'shouldn't stay here, it's
我不要在这里停留这是
The hexed chessboard!
Djanal Remember
what you promis
d Herikl
裘娜记得你答应
里克什么吧
Besides this must be a trap
可况
个
Yes, it is a trap
这是个陷阱
d
阱
Yes, it is a trap
这是个陷讲
but it's also a
direct way to Kwodahn
以直接找到科沃达
Eole, go - hide
风去找个地方藏起
风神我个地方藏赶来
起来
风神去我个
Eole, go hide
风神去找个地方藏起来
I knew I could
count on you, Princess
我就知道你值得期待公主殿下
This time. you shall forever
be a prisoner of this board
这次你会永远被囚禁在棋盘里
This is crazy
这太乱来了
邮器
rUeY II as uNy
And so will calibur!
幽然包御剑
)3
The piecessare
going to-appear soon!
)
I know I promised.
to protect yourPrincess
我知道自己答应过要保护你主殿下
but I'm just a little dragon
and I can only do so much okay?
可我只是条小龙能帮的很有限啊
Oh boy, here we go
天啊我们开始了
There they=are
他们来
How about one
final match Kwodahn?
最后一局如何啊科沃达
Winner takes all
然后胜出一方说了算
I know you're there! Answer me!
我知道你在那里回答我
I've been waiting for you, princess
我等候你多时了公主殿下
ve=been wantagh
princess
我知
hale-a-surgputise ftor our
我你
nown o andms B ewey
hake a sur
你
-hake_ surprise ftoe yous
我你
a8uds息
your
我你
lahaMe-a surprise ftop you
到③E叫
mow oy
m◎
宝生
斗
mown oy easprdnusBeweyI
haw覆sum
我氧你
ShaMe_ surpr
yous
我送你个原怪
Father!
父王
The statue! We found it!
亲王的石雕我找到了
So now we can leave, right?
那现在我们可以离开了对吧
The knight will show the way
骑士会给大家引路
、动
How about letting
the dragon show the way
让小龙引路如
d)述
s
d从
了
They re moving
y
am
not surprised?
他们动起来了我怎么就不意外呢
=
A
《
Father. Can you hear me?
父王能听到我说话吗
LOOk-OL
EElerie's-another one!
小心那边又过来了个
Th
omer laser Com
Come closer! Come on
再来一点来啊
y
Easy, Jolie
放轻松茱莉
E
So Princess Djana
has doomed us all
那么说是裘娜公主让我们走向灭亡了
This is hardly
the time to cast blame
现在不是归昝谁的责任的时
The kingdom will be destroyed
因为她为了
交还神剑
because she has
kept Xcalibur to herself.
整个王国将被
That's enough
够了
Prince Duncan is right-
we have plen
ty
肯亲王说得对我们有不作要
Have all the refugees
ed into the palao
把所有避难者引来
And you, prince Duncan
you will see to our defenses
而你邓肯亲王去查看
一下我们的防御工事
Mother, look!-
he light is turningsredy
Mother. look!
h山hsmg
The light is turning red
那光变红了
And all those birds
还有那
么
Don't let them get near you!
不要让那些鸟兵靠近自己
Look out! Behind you
小心你后面
One more down
消灭
You know, Princess
were quite a team, you and-I
公主知我是不错的拍挡
你和我
You known Princes
were rumle a使 am you-and
公服娜道吗我解是不昔的哦
就你和我
≥
Ah! Go back to
where you came from
从哪来你就回哪去吧
Wip! Wip, where are you?
威普威普你在哪
My poor little wip
Kowdahn! You are a coward
科沃达你是个懦夫
preMo aIe no人 iuyepMoy
Kowdahn! You are a coward!
Show yourself!
Face me so I can destroy you
我来消灭你
Here we go!
我们出发
Shogi Island, here we come
三基寺岛我们来了
Fire emanations.
火球去
F
y
Everyone!
Take shelter in the monastery!
大家赶快进去三基寺躲一躲
Quick! Quick
Tara
塔拉
iee⊥
ara!
塔拉
It's Herik!
He's going to crash
是哈里克他要撞礁了
It's Herik
是哈里克
Father! Can you hear me?
父王你听得到我说话吗
Evil for good shall you perform.
你会恩将仇报
m
Forgive me, father!
原谅我父王
Pom。他h
原我三
Forgie me, father
原费
Father! ather! You're alive
父王父王你活过来了
Diana, my little girl. at last!
裘娜我的小丫头终于见到你了
Djana, my little girl.. at last!
I knew [d=-find you! I knew/it
我就知道我会找到你的我就知道
影
我就知道我会我到你的我知道
I knew=t'dfind you! lknew-it
我就知道我会我到你的我就知道
Ahl Nok
啊
Ah山No
Ah! No!
啊不
Father!
Fath
王救我
Herik
哈里克
Herik, are you all right?
哈里克你没事吧
Answer me!
回答我
Tara! The Book of Life
must be returned to its place
塔拉必须把生命之书放回原位
4上
Kwodahn's lair! I finally made it
科沃达的老巢我终于找到它了
I've broken your spell, Kwodahn!//
我已经破除了你的魔咒科沃达
My father is alive and free
我父王活过来了他自由了
And I'm not
afraid of you any more
而我不会再怕你了
I never was!
我从来就没怕过你
You're wrong
你错了
Xcalibur will destroy you!
神剑会消灭你的
To do that. it would use
up all your vital powers
如果想那么做神剑会耗尽你的生命
You aren't going to
give up on me, are you?
你不会让我死心的
Why would Xcalibur do that?
神剑怎么可能会那样对我
Because you are
both in the heart of evil!
因为此刻你们的心都是邪恶的
It's too late. now
可惜现在晚了
Xcalibur can't help you!
神剑帮不了你
will destroy you all
我会把你们都毁灭
Herik and the
Shogis will defeat you!
哈里克和法师们会打败你的
They still have the Book of Life
他们还有生命之书帮忙
Ah yes, the Shogis
啊没错还有那些法师
Let's see how well
they are defeating me
我们就看看他们如何打败我吧
P
八
You'll make
a handsome trophy!
你会是个不错的战利品
Sorry to disappoint you!
抱歉让你失望了
They mustn't make it
不能让他们得逞
Run, We'll take care of them!
快跑我们会招呼他们
y
Go!
走啊
Meet me at the Library
我们在书库碰头
N
Your Shogi friend is persisten
你的术士朋友还真顽固啊
but you have run
out of time, little princess
可惜你没时间了小公主
ven if he replaces the Book
Xcalibur will stay here forever.
即使他放回生命之书
神剑也会永远留在这里了
Xcalibur hasn't lost all its powers
神剑并没有失去全部能量
or else you would have
finished me off already
否则你早就把我干掉了
And as long as I'm holding
只要我还握着神剑
I stand a chance to destroy you!
就有机会消灭你
Why waste my energy
何必浪费我的精力呢
Xcalibur will
exhaust you soon enough
神剑很快就会让你筋疲力尽的
then you'll drop it
and be at my mercy!
到时候你就会放下它向我求饶了
A
⑤
Master
大法师
By returning the
Book of Life today
今天你成功放回了生命之书
)you have justified my faith -in you
没有辜负我对你的期望
ou have proven yourself worthy
你证明了自己有这个能力
and from this day, the Bock
s yours to keep and protec
从今独后生命之书交给你保管
But I will need
you
voyage
不过我的最后次旅行需要你的助
Get ready Herik
准备好哈里克
A
Herik?
哈里克你好吧
M
The time has come
for- the final reckoning
是算总帐的时候了
You are tired
你筋疲力尽了
You know the end is near
你也知道一切都要结束了
Herik! I haven't
got any strength left
哈里克我一点力气都没有了
Xcalibur will give you more
神剑会赐予你力量的
少
So eager to die, young Shogi?
那么想死吗小术士
So my brother
自
Refuse to
learn the, most si
lessons
你解没有吸取教以
母
E自
再
These young people
have brought me to you.
这些年轻人把我带来了这里
he Shogi Master
大法师
You sought power for its own sake
为了提升自身的法力
and chose fear
and hate as your weapons
你选择了恐惧和憎恨作为武器
But don't you see?
可难道你没有看到吗
These/ children
carry
heir hearts
这些孩子御心里拥有的
all they ever needed to
stand up to your evil work
正足以抵抗你的邪恶法力
May light come: after darkness
愿黑暗过局是光明
Djana and Herik have
kept shogi knowledge well
裘娜和哈里克很好地保护了三基寺文明
They've preserved the knowledge
of the Shogis in the Book of-Life
他们保护了生命之书里所有的三基寺智慧
and the power of
the Sylphs in Xcalibur
也保存了神剑里的精灵法
Look. brother
兄弟看
Our Sylph sisters are with us
精灵姐妹们也聚齐了
Now. every g
force stands before you
刻所有正义力量都站在你面前
You are helpless against
这样一来你应该毫无反抗之力了吧
No! I am not yourbrother
我跟你不是兄弟
reject you all
我拒绝承认你们所有
我拒绝派认你们所有
I rejecteyou all
我拒绝承你们所有
r
the brothers reunite
当兄弟重聚
put up your sword,
and end your fight
举起手中的剑结束决斗
Go. children
你们离开这里吧孩子
The Final Combat is over
最后一战结束了
The brothers will reunite
兄弟即将聚首
and depart from this world forever
并且永远离开这个世界
The mirror, quick!
从镜子里出去快
and your dark spells are undone
你的魔咒也会失效
The Kingdom will live
n peace once again!
整
]又会恢复和平空宁
The kingdom will le
The kingdom will live
in peace once againl
整
日分恢复潮平安
b
岁
=
King Arthus, thank you, Djana
我阿瑟斯国王非常感谢你娜
And you, Herik, for
um,all your brave deeds
还有你哈里克感谢你们的英勇表现
As for you. Tara
塔拉为了表示对你的奖赏
we hereby name
you Prince
the sea
伽现在恩子你海公些头衔
bound noy
owen Ageney ew
we hereby name
you Princess of the Sea.
我们现在授予你海公主头衔
面
Am I doing alright, mother?
我做得对吗
Excellent, Arthur
非常棒阿瑟
Diana, my daughter.
take m
y helmet
裘娜我的女儿拿着我的头盔
and may it protect you and
bring you luck as it did for me
愿它能保护你并且如同带给我好运那样
也给你带去
Please excuse me
抱失陪一下
I'Il never be as happy
as when I found you, father
找回你我真的再高兴不过了父王
Herik?
哈里
么了
A
k
a
Come to me, Herik. my son
来找我吧哈里克我的孩子
I've been waiting so
g
我等你来找我在等得久了
W
Herik, wait for me!
哈里克等等我
I'm coming with you
Wherever you go
你去哪就跟你去哪
Father gave me his blessing!
父王祝福我了
That's fantastic!
太好了
Yes. Herik
We are as free as the wind!
没错哈里克我们象风一样自由了
SCRIPT SUPERTISOR
nu
EIECUTTY
ORT EDITOR
execuTIo SOM DITOR
MOLtg24Xo15 DAlLnDDXI
oscans pnss
ueue luBeron
ICCUTTYE STORY EDITOR
KTISTS
execuTE STORT EDT9
R115TS
YoLo⊥5
ansOn AIDS
o QD ANOIS DAun53rD
PT CONsU
SToMOABORe TS
STUDIO MANKE
STUDO MAN
ALLIPSE
PPDDUCTION KDMIMISTRX TOR- TOONCKH PRODUCTIONS Ill
PRODUCTION KOMIMISTRATOR
PRODUCTION XDMINISTRATOR- TOONCAN PRODUCTION Il INC
3D- MODELING
3D・ MODELINE
GRIBouILLe
3D-MODELING
GRIBOUILLE
PRODUCTIOH SECKETTRY
GRIBOVILLE
段A
二心了y
T脑P
PEOOUCTIOH Se
ioL性H9re
VISORS
器
TiRo
XRTs了S
MODeL
H冷E
出
MOTION CAPTURE
MOTION CAPTURe
SIUICON STUDIO
MOTION CKPTURe
MOTION CAPTURE
SIUCON STUDIO
磁
C6C6 INC
execu
PRODUCTION SUPenSOR
CECE INC
WXN SHOT
CGCS INC
H
TO Y5KO TISO
PRODUCTION MKNK6GR
C6C6 INC
RecuT saucer
PRODUTO FxO TIsO
rRODHTTON SUN素
PRODUCTION SUPerTIso
roy器
ROugh8H器xsor
器
LITOuT a
SUPERYISOR
xou∝凳是排5enso
rec"o累
ec TOCT EReSTOR
DoW NOLLYX1STKIWGY 3HO MLDN
surpasson
KasHtan
rec段
NETWORK AD
OMAUTAATOR
TONN段o
mas器5 SupervIsor
NETwO LTOMILTRATOR
TS SUPGRTISO翼
erx是eHN6
沿数 SUPERTIS
Lh在
是帮8To
eHTIN& C SP
eaTeRs TsT sur
N
MISTKATOK
国ms器 ecTs SuPErvIsor
UeNTIMs& Sete T reson
TS SUPERvISOR
suPeRVISOR
I ODReUEE
I oDmut
It oPnet
m
H
HHSTOPHE Dn
TOONCAN PRODUCTIONS xIl
盔
TOONCKN PRODUCTIONS XII
POST.PR
POST-PRoDuO
P吧sog
oo红点prw
RDTIM DERNNE
SouND MITER
YTR OPERTTORS
翻译：英语辅导频道
输入/时间轴/压制：harry159821/黑月
校对：